Guide to the World Federation of Trade Unions Records
World Federation of Trade Unions Records
- 1959-1973 (Box 4)
  - World Trade Union Committee for Consultation and United Action against the Monopolies., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    "Report. Joint Trade Union Action for the Development of International Trade and Economic Relations in the Interests of the Workers and Peoples by Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU," December 14-17, 1966, 101 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - Federation Syndicale Mondiale, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    "54e session du Bureau Executif de la FSM Rapport sur l'etat des activities de propagande de la FSM et les possibilities d 'amelioration dans ce domain - Rapporteur: V.A. Podzerko, Secretary de la FSM," April 11-13, 1967, 40 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    "34th session of the Executive Committee - Report on 'The Development of the WFTU's Work in the United Nations (UNO) and its specialized agencies' - "Speaker: Stan Dragoni, Secretary of the WFTU," October 25-27, 1967, 37 page mimeographed typescript. "34th session of the Executive Committee - Report on the work of the WFTU in developing new international trade union relationships and the united action of workers and union organizations all over the world in the cause of the well-being, liberty and independence of people for peace, and against imperialist acts of aggression, particularly in Vietnam and the Middle East - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary WFTU," October 25-27, 1967, 35 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions; Federation Syndicale Mondiale, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    WFTU: "34th session of the Executive Committee - (Resolutions and Decisions, Numbers 1-18)," 27 page mimeographed typescript. FSM: "Service de Presse de la FSM," (1967) 22 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    "(Documents adopted by the World Trade Unions Conference on Vocational Training, February 1-4, 1968)" 15 page mimeographed typescript
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    "18th session of the General Council Report on the first item on the agenda - The WFTU's activities in the present situation to develop international trade union unity for the triumph of the economic and social demands of the working class of peace and of national independence, and to put a definite end to American imperialism's aggression in Vietnam - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, Assistant General Secretary of the World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU)," December 16-19, 1968, 45 page mimeographed typescript. "18th session of the General Council Report on the second item on the agenda - The WFTU's work for training trade union officials - Speaker: Edvin Chleboun, Secretary of the WFTU," December 6-9, 1968, 21 page mimeographed typescript. "18th session of the General Council Report on the third item on the agenda - Convocation and preparation of the 7th World Trade Union Congress," December 6-9, 1968, 6 page mimeographed typescript, brittle.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    "18th session of the General Council (Drafts; Resolutions and Decisions," December 16-19, 1968, 50 page mimeographed typescript. "18th session of the General Council Plan of Work until the 7th World Trade Union Congress - Appendix to the reports presented tot eh Council," December 16-19, 1968, 27 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    "35th session of the Executive Committee - 3rd point of the agenda - Report on requests for affiliations - Speaker: Mahendra Sen, Secretary of the WFTU," December 15, 1968, 15 page mimeographed typescript. "35th session of the Executive Committee - (Resolutions and Decisions Numbers 1-7)," December 15, 1968, 9 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    "Document on trade union policy and action for preparation of the 7th World Trade Union Congress," June 5, 1969, 39 page mimeographed typescript. "7th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) - Report on the first point on the agenda - The role, tasks, and responsibilities of the WFTU and trade unions for workers in the struggle for social progress, trade union and democratic liberties, national independence, peace, against monopolistic exploitation, imperialism, colonialism and neo- colonialism - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU) Assistant Secretary General," October 17-26, 1969, 108 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    "7th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) - 1st report on the second point of the agenda - The situation in Vietnam and the struggle of workers and people of Vietnam against the American imperialist aggressors for the restoration of peace in Vietnam and for the development of solidarity of the workers and the people of the world - Speaker: Hoang Quoc Viet, President of the Federation of Trade Unions of Vietnam," October 17-26, 1969, 20 page mimeographed typescript. "7th WTUC - 2nd report on the second point of the agenda - Speaker: Tran Hoi Nam, Member of the permanent committee of the Trade Union Federation for the liberation of South Vietnam," October 17-26, 1969, 17 page mimeographed typescript. "7th WTUC - Report on the third point of the agenda - The problems of trade unions in developing countries - Speaker: Ibrahim Zakaria, WFTU Secretary," October 17-31, 1969, 45 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    "7th WTUC - Report on the 4th point of the agenda - The trade unions and scientific and technical progress," October 17-31, 1969, 38 page mimeographed typescript. "Constitution of the WFTU," 1969, 25 page mimeographed typescript.
  - 7th World Trade Union Congress; World Federation of Trade Unions, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    "7th World Trade Union Congress - Speech by Comrade Luciano Lama, Secretary of the General Confederation of Italian Workers (CGI) October 17-26, 1969, 30 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "Speech by President of AUCCTU Comrade A.N. Chelepin at the 7th World Trade Union Congress," 1969, 24 page booklet. WFTU: "(documents for preparation and discussion of 25th anniversary of London Conference)" December 18, 1969, 11 page mimeographed typescript.
  - Federation Syndicale Mondiale (FSM); World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    FSM: "Rencontre Syndicale Internationale a l'occasion du 25eme anniversaire de la Conference Syndicale Mondiale de Londres," January 30-February 1, 1970, 7 page mimeographed typescript. WFTU: "International Trade Union meeting on the occasion of the 25th anniversary of the London World Trade Union Conference - Conclusions of Brother Pierre Gensous, General Secretary of the WFTU," January 30-February 1, 1970, 6 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "International Trade Union meeting on the present problems of trade union unity and the lessons in unity from the 1945 conference - Introductory speech - Pierre Gensous, General Secretary, WFTU," January 30-February 1, 1970, 18 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions; Federation Syndicale Mondiale, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    WFTU: "Session of the (Executive) Bureau" February 24-26, 1970, 24 page mimeographed typescript. "Documents adopted by the WFTU Bureau at its meeting in Khatoum, February 24-26, 1970," March 4, 1970, 10 page mimeographed typescript. "Meeting of European Trade Union Centres affiliated to the WFTU - Report - Presented by Brother Sandro Stimuli, Secretary of the WFTU," June 25-26, 1970, 17 page mimeographed typescript. FSM: "Service Europe - Queloues considerations sur le cadre economique et social, sur la nature, la signification et les perspectives des luttes ouvriers en Europe en 1969," June 1970, 22 page mimeographed typescript
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    "2nd session of the WFTU Bureau - 2nd point on the agenda - Report on the development of the WFTU's activity in Asia - Speaker: Mehendra Sen, Secretary of the WFTU," October 8-10, 1970, 21 page mimeographed typescript. "2nd session of the WFTU Bureau - General Outline Work - Program of the WFTU for improved implementation of the policies adopted at the 7th World Trade Union Congress," October 8-10, 1970, 40 page mimeographed typescript. "List of documents adopted by the 2nd session of the WFTU Bureau," October 8-9, 1970, 13 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    "20th Session of the WFTU General Council - Report on the first item on the agenda - The WFTU's responsibilities in increasing and strengthening unity amongst trade unions for the satisfaction of the worker's demands and aspirations - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, General Secretary, WFTU," October 13-16, 1970, 39 page mimeographed typescript. "20th Session of the WFTU General council - Account of the WFTU's Activity from the 7th Congress (1969) to the General council (1970)," October 13-16, 1970, 45 page mimeographed typescript. "List of documents adopted by the 20th session of the WFTU General Council," October 13-16, 1970, 7 page mimeographed typescript. "20th Session of the WFTU General Council - Conclusions of Brother Pierre Gensous, General Secretary of the WFTU," October 13-16, 1970, 7 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    "3rd session of the WFTU Bureau - 1st item on the agenda - Speech - '100 years ago in Paris a new dawn was born for the international working class: the Paris commune' Speaker: Benoit Frachon, President of the CGT," April 21-23, 1971, 2 page typescript, brittle. 3rd session of the WFTU Bureau - 2nd item on the agenda - Report on the main aspects of the development of the situation since the General Council and the tasks arising therefrom for the WFTU - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, General Secretary, WFTU," April 21-23, 1971, 23 page typescript, brittle. "3rd session of the WFTU Bureau - 3rd item on the agenda - Report on the activities of the WFTU and the TUIs and the national affiliated centres at the United Nations with particular reference to the ILO - Speaker: Ibrahim Zakaria, Secretary of the WFTU," April 21-23, 1971, 21 page typescript, brittle. "3rd session of the WFTU Bureau - Conclusions drawn by Pierre Gensous, General Secretary, WFTU on the 2nd and 3rd items," April 21-23, 1971, 4 page mimeographed typescript. "Report on the study days on multinational companies," April 26-27, 1971, 6 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. "(General Secretary's conclusions and documents adopted at the 3rd session of the WFTU Bureau)," April 28, 1971, 17 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU); Federation Syndicale Mondiale (FSM), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    WFTU: "21st session of the WFTU General Council - 1st item on the agenda - Report " The present aspects of the international trade union movement and the resultant tasks for the WFTU," December 11-13, 1971, 26 page mimeographed typescript, brittle. FSM: "21eme session du Conseil General de la FSM - 2eme point a l'ordre du jour - Rapport sur l'activite des UIS," December 10-13, 1971, 13 page mimeographed typescript. "21eme session du Conseil General de la FSM - 3eme point a l'ordre du jour - Rapport sur la presse et propagande de la FSM," December 10-13, 1971, 11 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    "(Information Report on the Consultive meeting regarding the work ta the ILO," February 28, 1972, 9 page mimeographed typescript. "Account of the first meeting between representatives of special institutes and centers of trade union studies and the WFTU within the framework of future reciprocal cooperation in the light of the 8th World Trade Union Congress," September 8-9, 1972, 6 page mimeographed typescript. "Document on the monetary crisis - Prepared by the WFTU's working group" (1972), 24 age mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    "22nd session of the WFTU General Council - Account of activities of the WFTU between October 1971 and September 1972," October 31-November 3, 1972, 47 page mimeographed typescript. "22nd session of the WFTU General Council - Report on the meeting of the WFTU delegation with the Secretary-General of the United Nations and on its other meetings and consultations," November 1-3, 1972, 13 page mimeographed typescript. "22nd session of the WFTU General Council - First item on the agenda - Report 'Thee main problems of international trade union movement in the recent period, consequent work in coming months and especially in view of the 8th World Trade Union Congress," November 1-3, 1972, 28 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    "22nd session of the General Council Information on the meeting of the Working Group on the problems of working women," November 1-3, 1972, 5 page mimeographed typescript. "Conclusions of Pierre Gensous, WFTU General Secretary at the 22nd session of the WFTU General Council," November 1-3, 1972, 9 page mimeographed typescript. "22nd session of the WFTU General Council - (Resolutions; Decisions and appeals,)" November 1-3, 1972, 17 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    "Document for Bureau members for the discussing of the preparations for the 8th World Trade Union Congress at the 6th session of the WFTU Bureau," (1973), 6 page mimeographed typescript. "8th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) - Information concerning WFTU's activity in the field of trade union education in Asia Africa and Latin America between the seventh and eight WTUC - Speaker: I. Zakaria, WFTU Secretary," October 15-22, 1973, 8 page mimeographed typescript. "8th WTUC - Charter of the trade union rights and economic and social demands of the present time - Draft," October 15-22, 1973, 41 page mimeographed typescript. "(CGIL's proposed amendments to the constitution of the WFTU at the 8tjh WTUC)," October 15-22, 1973, 3 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    "Opening speech for the 8th WTUC - Speaker: Pierre Gensous, WFTU General Secretary," October 15-22, 1973, 34 page mimeographed typescript. "8th WTUC - Policy Document (draft)," October 15-22, 1973, 65 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    "8th WTUC - (draft) Co-Report on Asia - Speaker: S.A. Dange, Member, WFTU Bureau," October 15-22, 1973, 33 page mimeographed typescript. "8th WTUC - (draft) Co-Report on Latin America - Speaker: Lazaro Pena, Member, WFTU Bureau," October 15-22, 1973, 10 page mimeographed typescript. "8th WTUC (draft) - Co-report on the situation in Africa presented by Vilon Gubzo, Member, WFTU Bureau," October 15-22, 1973, 11 page mimeographed typescript.
  - World Federation of Trade Unions; Federation Syndicale Mondiale (Box 4, Folder 37)
    WFTU: "8th WTUC - (draft) Co-Report on Europe - Speaker: Georges Seguy, CGT General Secretary," October 15-22, 1973, 11 page mimeographed typescript. "8th World Trade Union Congress (WTUC) - Co-Report on the Middle East by Elias Habre, President of the National trade Union Federation of Lebanese Workers and Employees (FENASOL)," October 15-22, 1973, 6 page mimeographed typescript. "8th WTUC - Report on activities and plans of the Working Group on Young Workers - Speaker: H. Sinno, Chairman of the Working Group," October 15-22, 1973, 9 page mimeographed typescript. FSM: "VIIIeme Congress Syndicale Mondiale - Information du groups de travail des Ingenieurs, Cadres et Technicians - Rapporteur: Rene Le Guen, President du Group de Travail," October 15-22, 1973, 8 page mimeographed typescript.